Don Grisham collection, Inclusive: 1947-1964, Bulk: 1963-1964
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
Don Grisham collection
Inclusive: 1947-1964, Bulk: 1963-1964
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
108
Grisham, Don
2 document boxes.
The Don Grisham collection contains material relating to the assassination of President John F. Kennedy including transcriptions of police radio transmissions, correspondence, and investigation files from the Dallas Police Department. The collection also contains material related to Lee Harvey Oswald and his family prior to 1963.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Originals/Duplicates
All copies.
Biography/Profile
Donald Hugh Grisham was born on July 26, 1960, in Waco, Texas. He earned a Bachelor of Arts in History from Tarleton State University and worked as a filing clerk at the Attorney General's Office in Austin, Texas.
Grisham’s interest in the John F. Kennedy assassination stems from a memory in which he and his father watched as Jack Ruby killed Lee Harvey Oswald on November 24, 1963. Grisham has had a strong interest in the JFK assassination but is not a self-ascribed researcher on the subject.
The materials in this collection were accumulated by Grisham in 1982, during his time in the state Attorney General's office. The office offered transfer of three copies of the materials to the Texas State Archive who declined because they already possessed copies. Grisham later gifted these copies to the Poage Legislative Library in 2007.
Scope and Content
The materials in the Don Grisham collection have an inclusive date range of 1947-1964, with the bulk spanning 1963-1964, in the days and months following the assassination of President John F. Kennedy.
The items in this collection are significant, because they contain information collected in the aftermath of the assassination of President Kennedy including transcriptions of police radio transmissions from the day of the assassination and first-person statements from each officer involved in the hunt for Oswald as compiled by Dallas Police Sheriff J.E. Bill Decker. Content also includes information about Lee Harvey Oswald and court cases his family were involved in prior to the JFK assassination.
Originally bound in notebooks and binders, the collection consists of photocopies of material held in the Texas State Archives. As such, the materials are in excellent condition.
Arrangement
The Don Grisham collection originally consisted of bound notebooks and reports that were loosely organized with no true chronological arrangement. Previously, the reports were spiral bound and the notebooks were housed in three-ring binders. No previous inventories existed for the collection prior to the latest round of processing.
The collection is now arranged into two series: I. Notebooks and II. Reports. Folders within each series are organized alphabetically by topic.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 108. Acquired 2007-00-00
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Loretta J. Dunbar papers, 1963
Dick Russell papers, Inclusive: 1924-2011, undated, Bulk: 1964-2003, undated
Gus Russo papers, Inclusive: 1932-2006, Bulk: 1953-1998
Gordon Schendel papers, Inclusive: 1964-1990, undated, Bulk: 1964-1970, undated
Related references
Don Grisham collection, Accession #108, Control File, Baylor Collections of Political Materials, W. R. Poage Legislative Library, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Assassination.; Oswald, Lee Harvey.
Places
Dallas (Tex.) -- History.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1963-1969.
Genres
Correspondence.; Records (Documents)
- Notebooks, 1961-1964; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Originals/Duplicates
  All copies.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. Notebooks contains material that was originally held in three-ring binders. The contents of these folders include police reports, material related to the Dallas Police Department's investigation of the assassination, and photographs.
  - Dallas Police (1 of 2), 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dallas Police (2 of 2), 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Investigation of the Assassination of the President (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Investigation of the Assassination of the President (2 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Investigation of the Operational Security Involving the Transfer of Lee Harvey Oswald — November 24, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Reports, 1947-1964; 2
  Series II. Reports contains previously spiral-bound documents. Materials contained in the series include police reports, court documents, correspondence, and transcriptions of police radio transmissions. Overall, the series is in excellent condition.
  - Dallas Police Report, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald Assassination — Nov. 22, 1963 Investigation by J.E. Bill Decker, Sheriff of Dallas County, Texas (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lee Harvey Oswald, 1947-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Marguerite C. Oswald vs King Candy Company", Final Judgement, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Marguerite C. Oswald vs Liberty Insurance Company of Texas", Final Judgement, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Officer J.D. Tippit, 1952-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Texas Supplement Report — Correspondence File (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Texas Supplement Report — Correspondence File (2 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Transcripts of Dallas Police Radio Transmissions (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Transcripts of Dallas Police Radio Transmissions (2 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)